If you have prior knowledge about the state space,
如果你以前就了解状态空间
you can manually design an appropriate discretisation scheme.
那么可以手动地设计相应的离散化方案
Like in our gears switching example,
就像在换挡示例中一样
we knew the relationship between fuel consumption and speed.
我们知道油耗和速度之间的关系
But in order to function in arbitrary environments,
但是为了在随机环境中正常运转
we need a more generic method.
我们需要一个更通用的方法
One elegant approach for this is tile coding.
一种比较合适的方式是 Tile Coding
Here, the underlying state space is continuous and two dimensional.
这里的底层状态空间是连续的二维空间
We overlay multiple grids or tilings on top of the space,
我们在该空间上方叠加多个网格或拼贴
each slightly offset from each other.
每层都稍微不对齐
Now, any position S in the state space can be
状态空间里的任何位置 S
coarsely identified by the tiles that it activates.
都可以粗略地通过它所激活的拼贴识别
If we assign a bit to each tile,
如果我们为每个拼贴分配一个位
then we can represent our new discretised state as a bit vector,
则可以将新离散化状态表示为位向量
with ones for the tiles that get activated, and zeros elsewhere.
激活的位置为 1 其他位置为 0
This, by itself, is a very efficient representation.
这种方法本身是一个非常高效的表示法
But the genius lies in how the state value function is computed using the scheme.
但是精彩之处在于如何使用该方案计算状态值函数
Instead of storing a separate value for each state V of S,
它由该状态的位向量和每个拼贴的权重定义
it is defined in terms of the bit vector for that state and a weight for each tile.
而不是为每个状态 V(s) 存储单独的值
The tile coding algorithm in turn updates these weights iteratively.
Tile Coding 算法然后迭代地更新这些权重
This ensures nearby locations that share tiles also share some component of state value,
这样可以确保共享拼贴的临近位置也共享状态值的一些部分
effectively smoothing the learned value function.
从而有效地使所学的值函数更加平缓
Tile coding does have some drawbacks.
Tile Coding 也具有一些缺点
Just like a simple grid based approach we have to manually select the tile sizes,
和简单的网格方法一样
there offsets, number of tilings,
我们需要提前手动选择拼贴大小
etc, ahead of time.
偏移量 拼贴数量等等
A more flexible approach is adaptive tile coding,
一个更加灵活的方式是 Adaptive Tile Coding
which starts with fairly large tiles,
先从非常大的拼贴开始
and divides each tile into two whenever appropriate.
然后在合适时将每个拼贴一分为二
How do we know when to split?
如何判断何时该拆分呢？
Well, we can use a hero stick for that.
我们可以采用试探法
Basically, we want to split the state space when we
也就是说 当我们意识到通过当前的表示法
realize that we are no longer learning much with the current representation.
不再学到很多规律时 即值函数不再改变
That is, when our value function isn't changing.
我们就需要拆分状态空间
We can stop when we have reached some upper limit on the number of splits,
当我们达到拼贴数量上限或迭代上限时
or some max iterations.
可以停止拆分
In order to figure out which tile to split,
为了判断应该拆分哪个拼贴
we have to look at which one is likely to have the greatest effect on the value function.
我们需要确定哪个拼贴最有可能对值函数的影响最大
For this, we need to keep track of subtiles and their projected weights.
为此 我们需要跟踪子拼贴以及它们的预测权重
Then, we can pick the tile with the greatest difference between subtile weights.
然后我们可以选择子拼贴之间权重差别最大的拼贴
There are many other heuristics you can use,
你还可以使用很多其他试探法
but the main advantage of adaptive tile coding,
不过 Adaptive Tile Coding 的主要优势是
is that it does not rely on a human to specify a discretisation ahead of time.
它不需要我们手动提前指定离散化方式
The resulting state space is appropriately partitioned based on its complexity.
最终得到一个基于空间复杂程度的状态空间的划分